e-healthcaresolutions.com 2019-06-17

# eHealthcare Solutions Privacy Policy

Last Updated: 4/19/2019

eHealthcare Solutions, LLC (“ **EHS** ”, “ **EHSX** ”, “ **we** ”, “ **us** ” or “ **our** ”) is a digital advertising network (“EHS”) and Exchange (sometimes referred to as EHSX) specializing in the healthcare and pharmaceutical industries.  EHS collects information in connection with the advertising management services it provides through its relationships with third party healthcare advertisers, publishers, medical societies and associations (the **“Services”** ).  This privacy policy (“ **Privacy Policy** ”) explains how EHS collects, uses, and discloses information on our website, located at [www.ehealthcaresolutions.com](http://www.ehealthcaresolutions.com/), as well as through our third party advertising networks and exchange (together, the “ **Websites** ”).  It is important to be aware that the Websites each have their own privacy policies which govern which information they do and do not collect and how they handle such information.  Therefore, we recommend that you review the privacy policy on each Website you visit.  EHS is not responsible for information gathered from or about you from any of the Websites.

This Privacy Policy is intended to notify you of our online privacy practices, the type of information that may be collected and stored, how the information is used, with whom the information may be shared, what choices are available to you regarding the collection, use and distribution of the information, what kind of security procedures are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under our control, and who to contact with questions or concerns.

**By using or accessing the Services or Websites and/or by contacting us and/or by providing any personal information, you consent to the collection and use of such information by us in accordance with this Privacy Policy.   ****If we decide to change our Privacy Policy, we will post those changes on this page.**

**Why We Collect Information:**

We collect personal information in order to provide the Services on and through the Websites and deliver information that you agree to receive from us.

**How We Collect Information:**

We collect information in three primary ways:

  1. **You Give Us Information** : We collect information from you when you submit it to us through the Websites or Services.
  2. **We Collect Information Automatically** : We automatically collect certain types of information when you visit or use the Websites or Services, or when you click on banners, advertisements or hyperlinks. For example, we automatically collect various types of technical information, such as the type of web browser you use, the time and date that you accessed the Websites, the pages or advertisements you visited and the amount of time you did so, and your location to the extent available.
  3. **We Collect Information from Other Sources** : We may obtain information about you from outside sources.  For example, we may obtain commercially or publicly available information about you from third-parties or purchase email lists from third-parties for advertising and marketing purpose or fraud detection/prevention.   We may also receive information from third-parties who provide services for us through web-beacons and other technologies as otherwise discussed in this Privacy Policy.

**What Information We Collect** **:**

We may collect, store and use information that can be used to identify you and that may be used to determine your use of the Websites or Services, or how the Websites should be made available to you.  This information includes:

  1. Information about your visits to and use of the Websites or Services;
  2. Information which will determine the country or region within a country from which you are accessing the Websites;
  3. Your browser preferred language; and/or
  4. Information that you provide to us directly or through any of the Websites, directly or indirectly (i.e., provided to us by the Websites as a result of your use thereof) or Services.

In addition, EHS may arrange for other companies to provide some of the Services, including in connection with the placement of advertisements on the Websites.  Such advertisements, and your viewing of such advertisements, is governed by this Privacy Policy and may also be governed by the third party’s Privacy Policy if and when you leave the Websites.

**Please do not submit any sensitive personal information or data to us, including but not limited to your: (i) racial or ethnic origin; (ii) political, philosophical or religious beliefs, including membership in a political party or trade union; (iii) physical or mental health, biometric details or genetic makeup; or (iv) sexual orientation or preferences. If any such information is submitted to us, it is at your own risk.**

**_General Browsing_** :

Even if you do not submit personal information through the Websites, we may gather navigational information about where visitors go on or through the Websites, what materials or advertisements they “click” or access, and information about the technical efficiencies of our services. This information allows us to provide our services to our clients and customers, as well as help us better understand the overall and individual Website user experience. This information also helps us improve the quality of our services to our clients and customers, as well as those visiting and using the Websites, by recognizing and delivering more of the features, areas, and services the Websites’ users prefer. In this process of gathering information, we may collect personally identifiable and non-personally identifiable information (for example, domain type, browser type and version, service provider and IP address, referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, email address, and click-stream data). We may also create and use electronic records to compile statistics about how our visitors collectively interact with the Websites.  We may also supplement this information with other available public or commercial databases to build out user profiles for improved targeting and to share with our advertisers for their services.

**_Mobile Browsing:_**

If you are accessing the Websites via a mobile device, information about your use of the Websites, as well as your mobile device type, carrier and location may be communicated to us, and your information may be shared with your mobile carrier or access provider.

**_Use of Cookies and Other Tracking:_**

We may use both session cookies and persistent cookies on the Websites.  Cookies are bits of electronic information that a website may transfer to a visitor’s computer to identify specific information about that visitor’s visits to that website. Session cookies or transient cookies are cookies that are stored in temporary memory and are not retained when the browser is closed. In other words, they are erased when you close your browser. Session cookies do not collect information from your computer and typically will store information in the form of a session identification that does not personally identify you.  Persistent cookies assign a unique identification to your computer and are typically stored on your computer’s hard drive and are used to help track clicks as you use or access the Websites, or to tell us whether you have previously visited the Websites.  Persistent cookies remain on your computer until affirmatively deleted by you.

We may also use cookies set by third-parties with whom we have entered into agreements which may enable us to obtain analytics information about the use of the Websites.  You can set your browser not to accept cookies or to notify you when you are sent a cookie, giving you the opportunity to decide whether or not to accept it.  You may also use commonly available tools in your browser to remove cookies which may have been placed onto your computer.

We may also use FLASH cookies.  FLASH cookies, also known as shared local objects, are cookies that are placed on your computer that are not removed through normal browser management tools.

We may also use traffic analysis software to track the use patterns of users of the Websites, and other technologies such as digital fingerprinting, browser cache, device IDs, or watermarking to identify the user of the Websites.

We may also use web beacons or clear .gifs.  Web beacons or clear .gifs, and similar technologies are pieces of code placed on a web page to collect data on the users of a specific web page.

**_Server Logs and Widgets:_**

We may use web server logs.  A web server log is a record of activity created by a computer that delivers certain webpages to your browser.  Certain activities that you perform utilizing the Websites or Services may record information in server logs, such as if you enter a search term into a search box located on the Services.  For example, the server log may record the search term(s) you use, or the link you clicked on to bring you to the Websites.  The server log may also record information about your browser, such as your IP address and the cookies set on your browser.

We may also use widgets.  A widget is generally an application that can be embedded in a webpage, and which can provide real-time information to the webpage.  Widgets are often provided by third-parties to enable collection of data about website usage.

**_General:_**

By using or accessing the Services or Websites and/or by contacting us and/or by providing any personal information, you give us your consent to track your activities using the technologies described above, as well as similar technologies developed in the future, and that we may use such tracking technologies in the emails we send you.

**How We Use the Information We Collect:**

We use the information we collect in a variety of ways.  Primarily, we use the information we collect to provide better Services to our clients and customers, as well as provide more targeted and better services to users of the Websites using all the technologies referenced above.

We also use the information we collect internally in our business for many business purposes, such as to: (i) provide and improve the Websites and Services; (ii) analyze trends and conduct research about improving the Services; (iii) provide support and respond to questions from customers of our Services and users of the Websites; (iv) provide targeting of advertisements and promotions; (v) learn about the users of the Websites, including authentication of the users identify; (vi) track traffic patterns and Services usage; (vii) provide customer service and technical support with respect to the Services; (viii) correlate information with other commercially available information to identify demographics and preferences to assist us in our Services and advertisement placements; (ix) provide specific relevant marketing, promotional, or other targeted or location-based content or information to our customers and users of the Websites and Services; (x) address information security and/or privacy practices, network functioning, engineering, and troubleshooting issues; (xi) investigate claims and/or legal actions, violations of law or agreements, and compliance with relevant applicable laws and legal process; (xii) comply with law, or based on our good faith belief that it is necessary to conform or comply with the law, or otherwise to disclose information to prevent fraud to reduce credit risks, to cooperate with police and other governmental authorities, or otherwise protect the rights of those individuals or entities we deem appropriate; and (xiii) process or engage in a sale of all or part of our business, or if we go through a reorganization or merger.

We may also share or sell personally identifiable information and non-personally identifiable information externally with our affiliates and business partners, as well as with other third-party service providers who help us provide operational services for the Websites, the Services and our business, which might include, but is not necessarily limited to: business entities that provide email address management and communication contact services, advertisers, publishers, retargeting services, network equipment and application management providers and hosting entities, entities which obtain information such as demographic information which might be aggregated with information we have about you, entities that allow us to personally identify visitors to the Websites, judicial, administrative and/or legal or financial accounting providers in the event that information must be reviewed or released in response to civil and/or criminal investigations, claims, lawsuits, or if we are subject to judicial or administrative process (such as a subpoena) to release your information or to prosecute or defend legal actions, and other service providers which may be involved in the other types of services and activities otherwise discussed in this Privacy Policy.

We may allow third-party companies to collect certain anonymous information when you visit our website. These companies may use non-personally identifiable information during your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. These companies typically use a cookie or a third party web beacon to collect this information. To learn more about this behavioral advertising practice, you can visit [www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/).

We may also use your personally identifiable information to contact you in ways other than email or regular mail, such as via telephone or SMS.

**Business Transfers**

If EHS or substantially all of its assets were acquired, or in the unlikely event that EHS goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, information we have gathered as explained herein would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third-party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of EHS may continue to use your personal information as set forth in this Privacy Policy.

**Your Choices about the Information We Collect**

If you do not consent to the way in which we may use your personal information, please do not submit any personal information to us.  If you do not wish to receive special offers and other promotions from us, click the unsubscribe link located in our emails or [opt out here](http://preferences-mgr.trustarc.com/?pid=ehealthcare01&aid=ehs_publisher01&type=ehs), and to the extent provided on the applicable Website.  If you do not wish to receive other marketing materials from us and/or if you do not want us to share your personal information with other entities as stated in this Privacy Policy, please provide us with your exact name and address and advise us that you wish to opt-out for information sharing or receiving information from us or both as the case may be.  Please direct your opt-out request to the following contacts:

**Email Address:   **

**Opt-Out Online:**

**[Opt-Out of Personally Identifiable Advertising and Data Sharing](http://ehealthcaresolutions.com/optout/)**

**Postal Address:   **

eHealthcare Solutions, LLC  
Attn: Chief Privacy Officer  
810 Bear Tavern Road, Suite 102  
Ewing, NJ 08628 **           **

**Privacy of Children Who Visit the Website**

We recognize the importance of children’s safety and privacy. The Websites are not designed to attract children, and the Services are not intended for use by any children under the age of 13. We do not request, or knowingly collect, any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13. If you have reason to believe that we have collected information pertaining to children under the age of 13 please contact us at [privacy@ehsmail.com](mailto:privacy@ehsmail.com) or 609-882-8887

**Your California Privacy Rights**

We collect various types of personal information about you during the course of your relationship with us. Under California law, if you are a resident of California, you may make a written request to us about how we have shared your information with third-parties for their direct marketing purposes. In response to your written request, we are allowed to provide you with a notice describing the cost-free means to opt-out of our sharing your information with third-parties with whom we do not share the same brand name, if the third-party will use such information for its direct marketing purposes.

If you would like to exercise your rights under California law, please send your written request to the email address or postal address below. Please include your postal address in your request. Within thirty (30) days of receiving your written request, we will provide you with a Third-party Direct Marketing Opt-Out Form so you may request that your personal information not be disclosed to third-parties for their direct marketing purposes.

**Email Address:**

**Postal Address:**

eHealthcare Solutions, LLC  
Attn: Chief Privacy Officer  
810 Bear Tavern Road, Suite 102  
Ewing, NJ 08628

**Visitors to the Website Outside of the United States**

If you are visiting the Websites or using the Services from a location outside of the United States, your connection will generally be through and to servers located in the United States. All information you receive from the Websites will be created on servers located in the United States, and all information you provide will be maintained on web servers and systems located within the United States. The data protection laws in the United States and other countries might not be as those in your country.  By using the Websites or Services and/or submitting information to us, you specifically consent to the transfer of your information to the United States to the facilities and servers we use, and to those with whom we may share your information.

**Links**

For your convenience, the Websites may contain links to other websites.  We are not responsible for the privacy practices, advertising, products, or the content of such other websites. None of the links should be deemed to imply that we endorse or have any affiliation with the links.

**Security**

We believe in providing a safe and secure experience for all of our online visitors. To that end, we have implemented security measures to protect the information collected from you. We maintain reasonable physical and electronic safeguards designed to limit unauthorized access to your personally identifiable information, and to protect you against the criminal misuse of that information.

While we use the foregoing security measures to protect your information, please note that no data transmitted over the Internet or stored and utilized for business purposes can be guaranteed to be completely secure.  No security measures are perfect or impenetrable.  We cannot guarantee that only authorized persons will view your information. We cannot ensure that information you share on the Website will not become publicly available. You can reduce these risks by using common sense security practices such as choosing a strong password, using different passwords for different services, and using up to date antivirus software.

**Please note that while we attempt to limit access to the information we obtain about you to those with whom we have agreed to share such information, we cannot guarantee that other parties will not gain access to our information and we cannot control their use of any information accessed via the Services or Websites.**

**DMD Healthcare Communications NetworkSM Privacy Statement**  
This digital service participates in the DMD Healthcare Communication NetworkSM (the “Network”), and as such has implemented various technologies for universal registration/login among all Network member websites. These technologies are managed by DMD Marketing Corp. (“DMD”), and may involve the collection, receipt, and sharing of information with DMD, its clients and other Network members. If you would like to understand how this digital service’s participation in the Network affects your privacy, please click here:

<http://usersupport.dmdconnects.com/PrivacyPolicy.htm>

**Questions / Changes in Notice**

If you have questions or concerns with respect to our Privacy Policy, you may contact us at [privacy@ehsmail.com](mailto:privacy@ehsmail.com). We may elect to change or amend our Privacy Policy; in such event, we will post the notice changes in our Privacy Policy on the Website.
